{
    "id": "dc18572ff8224b83870e7a1334a425a4",
    "title": "Synonyms Exerise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "The prisoner’s life was full of hardship and exertion. Here the word exertion can be replaced by …………………..",
            "description": "Travail can mean backbreaking work.",
            "answers": [
                "travesty",
                "tranquility",
                "travail"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "98e9089c303c4e8c9eb2e5f911585684"
        },
        {
            "question": "The comedian’s mockery of a senator making a speech was riotously funny. Here the word mockery can be replaced by …………………….",
            "description": "Travesty means mockery or ludicrous imitation.",
            "answers": [
                "travesty",
                "eulogy",
                "epithet"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "bb104c7eaa884fbbaac618322ff4abb2"
        },
        {
            "question": "In time of war, sedition is a crime punishable by death. The word sedition can be replaced by ………………….",
            "description": "Treason means infidelity or sedition. ",
            "answers": [
                "treason",
                "treasure",
                "treatise"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "e39ecd78967042059f91cf032914a063"
        },
        {
            "question": "Freezing rain made the road precarious. The word precarious can be replaced by ………………………",
            "description": "Treacherous means precarious.",
            "answers": [
                "precautionary",
                "treacherous",
                "prevalent"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b75a40ea7f9041f79b6abbe54aa4cc9b"
        },
        {
            "question": "The sinner prayed that his misdeeds would be forgiven. Here the word misdeeds can be replaced by …………………..",
            "description": "Transgression means wrongdoing or offence.",
            "answers": [
                "transmission",
                "transgressions",
                "piety"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "efa8a92eca414ee5933e85ec79c42e44"
        },
        {
            "question": "Youthful beauty is temporary. The word temporary can be replaced by",
            "description": "All of these words mean temporary.",
            "answers": [
                "transient",
                "transitory",
                "ephemeral",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3,
            "id": "1c492f41870f4f6896ae220713df15f5"
        },
        {
            "question": "The heat and lack of sleep made everyone sluggish. Here the word sluggish can be replaced by …………………..",
            "description": "Torpid means slow moving or inert.",
            "answers": [
                "torrid",
                "tortuous",
                "torpid"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "a93bbd65ef6945d0b9059f82f4324537"
        },
        {
            "question": "The principal delivered a tirade to the disobedient students. Here the word tirade can be replaced by ………………………..",
            "description": "The words diatribe and tirade both mean a volley of words usually of censure.",
            "answers": [
                "paean",
                "diatribe",
                "eulogy"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f1bfefc964dc4844af3bccccae58bcc4"
        },
        {
            "question": "Even though she had plenty of money, the old woman was very frugal. Here the word frugal can be replaced by ......................................",
            "description": "Thrifty means frugal or economical.",
            "answers": [
                "prodigal",
                "improvident",
                "thrifty"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "8a09e610a3ce49e48e2dd593d088c558"
        },
        {
            "question": "He was so tight-lipped that no one knew whether he enjoyed the party or not. Here the word tight-lipped can be replaced by ……………………….",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "eloquent",
                "verbose",
                "taciturn"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4cbbed4d6dbb4cab83f681527fb238fb"
        },
        {
            "question": "Stand up and fight for your rights instead of being submissive. Here the word submissive can be replaced by …………………………….",
            "description": "Docile means obedient and submissive.",
            "answers": [
                "docile",
                "domicile",
                "refractory"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "04fd407ea6764c6c9673797e4e3f2e6c"
        },
        {
            "question": "The mighty housing development dwarfed the rest of the neighborhood. Here the word mighty can be replaced by …………………………….",
            "description": "Stupendous means vast, mighty or enormous.",
            "answers": [
                "stupendous",
                "salient",
                "sagacious"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "7dc1aeefc3504f23adfb029f1e1187ad"
        }
    ]
}